OPERATIONS MANAGER

Education and Training

BS: Telecommunications and Film University of Oregon Telecommunications and Film

Instructional Design *Miller Heiman - Large Account Management Process, LAMP® Certification [Type text][Type text] Skill Highlights

- Professional Summary
- Specializing in Operations and Account Managment
- Providing extensive experience within several specialized healthcare sectors combined with entrepreneurial, relationship building, team building and implementation skills.
- Strategic planning
- Procedure development
- Cost reduction and containment
- Streamline Process
- · Project management
- Risk management & inventory control
- Analytical
- Motivator

Skills

Account Management, Streamline, advertising, budgets, budget, call center, content, contracts, Cost reduction, client, clients, customer service, customer care, data entry, database, decision-making, decision support, designing, dialysis, edit, Finance, financing, financial, hiring, Instructional Design, inventory management, inventory control, team building, Managment, market, Marketing, materials, network, print production, Procedure development, improving processes, program development, Project management, proposals, protocols, quality, relationship building, reporting, Risk management, Sales, scripts, staffing, Strategic planning, surgery, Type, website

Professional Experience

Operations Manager

January 2014 to Current Fleetcor il/4 Spartanburg, SC

- Family owned and extensively awarded Pacific Northwest/Walla Walla Valley winery.
- Increase Wine Club, Online and Tasting Room Sales by 30% through improving processes and implementation of centralized system.
- Analyze work process to improve fulfillment activities and improved deliverability of perishable products.
- Institute process to maintain adherence to state and federal compliance regulations.
- Provide reporting structure and oversight for sales and inventory management.
- Hire, train and manage tasting room staff.

Account Executive

January 2010 to January 2013 Aetna Inc. il/4 Kingston, NY

- Operates highly specialized outpatient centers in technology-based medical sectors.
- Provides clinics in their network with a full suite of management services, infrastructure and treatment financing for self-pay patients.
- Responsible for growing financial products and services for self-paid elective surgery patients Expanded use of programs by 11% in one
 year through launching new products, improving operations for existing products and training of financial coordinators in a mature market
 place with limited growth.
- Launched new online tools to 100% of assigned customers in a three-month period.
- Field Liaison for Operations, Finance, Marketing and Clinical Team to develop new offering based on customer insights.
- Created opportunities for product and relationship expansion through consistent, responsive customer care.

Account Manager

January 1998 to January 2004 Instacart il/4 Coinjock, NC

- World's largest provider of dialysis products and services.
- Analyzed membership data, compare and summarize medical and pharmaceutical claims data to facilitate client contract annual reconciliation, to realize annual cost savings.
- Mentored and supported new and existing account managers.
- Launched, managed, expanded client programs and developed enduring client relationships.
- Key tasks include: client program development, results synthesis, project management for new client launch and ongoing client communication.
- Managed operations department that included hiring and developing customer service and data integrity staff.
- Developing and designing client reports, determine staffing needs, develop data entry and data integrity procedures, purchase and administrate call center system and membership software Created implementation materials for new clients.
- Designed and instituted plan for member and provider communications.
- Created and implemented process for responding to request for proposals.

Senior Producer

January 1997 to January 1999 Keywords Studios i¹/₄ Burbank, CA

• Leading provider to consumers, healthcare professionals, and brands with content and advertising-based services.

- Created budgets, proposals and contracts based on customer requirements.
- Effectively managed project costs to stay within budget, including actualizing budget upon project completion.
- Scheduled guests and engineers, develop scripts for talk show, direct talent and edit final program for replay on website.

Account Manager

January 1991 to January 1997 Instacart il/4 Colden, NY

- Provider of health care decision support services.
- The company's database comprises clinical guidelines that incorporate consensus medical protocols and decision-making tools to address common health concerns.
- Increased levels of responsibility in Account Management with direct management of up to 40 national accounts.
- Negotiated renewal contracts meeting goal of 90% business renewal.
- Up-sell to 80% of eligible customer base for an additional \$1.7 million in revenue.
- Managed \$1.2 million dollar print production budget, instigated and executed new program which decreased costs by using recycled materials while improving quality of mailings.